nwhm.org 2019-12-12

# Donor Privacy Policy | National Women's History Museum

**Donor Privacy Policy**

The National Women's History Museum (NWHM) researches, collects and exhibits the contributions of women to the social, cultural, economic and political life of our nation in a context of world history. The museum will use innovative and engaging means including permanent and online exhibits, educational programs, and outreach efforts to communicate the breadth of women's experiences and accomplishments to the widest possible audience. The sharing of this knowledge will illuminate and encourage women and men, people of all classes, races and cultures to move into the future with respect, equal confidence, greater partnership, and opportunity.

Contributions from NWHM Board members, individual donors, corporations and foundations make up approximately 100% of NWHM's base of support and our relationship with our contributors is the highest expression of our mutual commitment to the mission of mainstreaming women's history.

NWHM respects the privacy of our donors and has put in place a Donor Privacy Policy to honor these rights.

**Donor information**

NWHM collects and maintains the following types of donor information when it is voluntarily provided to us:

  * Contact information such as name, address, telephone number and e-mail address
  * Giving information
  * Information on events attended, publications received and special requests for program information
  * Information provided by the donor in the form of comments and suggestions

This confidential information is kept on file for IRS purposes. It is also used to analyze overall giving patterns in order to make more accurate budget projections, as well as to understand donors' interests in our mission and to update them on the organization's plans and activities. This information is shared with certain staff members, Board members and consultants only on a confidential and need-to-know basis. Each person has signed a Confidentiality Agreement to further protect the privacy of the donor information.

All the above information is collected to help us tailor our content and personalize our donors and supporters' experience. The Museum may use this information to send our donor's email announcements, or mailings, updates on our programs and scholar activities. Donors may opt-out of these communications at any time.

**List sharing**

NWHM occasionally rents or exchanges information with other like-minded non-profit organizations. We honor the request of any donor who has asked that NWHM not rent or exchange their name and address information and their records are so marked on our database and excluded from this rental process. NWHM never sends out mailings on behalf of other organizations.

**Discontinuing contact upon request**

It is the policy of NWHM to communicate with donors according to their expressed preferences whenever possible. NWHM will discontinue or change the method used to contact any person upon that person's oral or written request directed to the organization, its professional fundraiser, or other agent.

NWHM shall maintain a record of all requests by persons who indicate to the Museum, its professional fundraiser, or other agents, that they do not wish to be contacted by or on behalf of the National Women's History Museum.

The National Women's History Museum does not knowingly collect information from children. See our Web Privacy and Use Policy for details on information collected during web browsing and site terms of use.

**Security and Enforcement**

The National Women's History Museum protects your personal information from loss, misuse, alteration, or unauthorized disclosure by encrypting the data which you provide us with current encryption tools, including HTTPS (Hyper Text Transfer Protocol Secure) and SSL (Secure Socket Layer) protocols and by requiring employees with access to personal data to comply with our privacy policy. We operate secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection systems. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorized individuals have access to the information provided by our donors.
